<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>CodeAvenge</title>
    <link href="https://codeavenge.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://codeavenge.com" />
    <updated>2023-08-13T21:29:57+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Anindra</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://codeavenge.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Privacy policy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/privacy-policy/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/privacy-policy/</id>
        <media:content url="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/17/privacy-policy-g905f2d15d_640.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-08-13T21:29:57+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/17/privacy-policy-g905f2d15d_640.jpg" alt="Privacy Policy" />
                    At android app or website, accessible from my android app and website, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by android app and how we use it. If&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/17/privacy-policy-g905f2d15d_640.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Privacy Policy" /></p>
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;At android app or website, accessible from my android app and website, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by android app and how we use it.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;This Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in android app. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Consent&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Information we collect&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;The personal information that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide your personal information.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;If you contact us directly, we may receive additional information about you such as your name, email address, phone number, the contents of the message and/or attachments you may send us, and any other information you may choose to provide.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;When you register for an Account, we may ask for your contact information, including items such as name, company name, address, email address, and telephone number.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;How we use your information&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;We use the information we collect in various ways, including to:&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Provide, operate, and maintain our website&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Improve, personalize, and expand our website&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Understand and analyse how you use our website and app&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Develop new products, services, features, and functionality&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Communicate with you, either directly or through one of our partners, including for customer service, to provide you with updates and other information relating to the website, and for marketing and promotional purposes&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Send you emails&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Find and prevent fraud&quot;]]]],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Log Files&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;android app follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services">
<div>
<p>At android app or website, accessible from my android app and website, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by android app and how we use it.</p>
<p>If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.</p>
<p>This Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in android app. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.</p>
<h2>Consent</h2>
<p>By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms.</p>
<h2>Information we collect</h2>
<p>The personal information that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide your personal information.</p>
<p>If you contact us directly, we may receive additional information about you such as your name, email address, phone number, the contents of the message and/or attachments you may send us, and any other information you may choose to provide.</p>
<p>When you register for an Account, we may ask for your contact information, including items such as name, company name, address, email address, and telephone number.</p>
<h2>How we use your information</h2>
<p>We use the information we collect in various ways, including to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Provide, operate, and maintain our website</li>
<li>Improve, personalize, and expand our website</li>
<li>Understand and analyse how you use our website and app</li>
<li>Develop new products, services, features, and functionality</li>
<li>Communicate with you, either directly or through one of our partners, including for customer service, to provide you with updates and other information relating to the website, and for marketing and promotional purposes</li>
<li>Send you emails</li>
<li>Find and prevent fraud</li>
</ul>
<h2>Log Files</h2>
<p>android app follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services' analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.</p>
<h2>Advertising Partners Privacy Policies</h2>
<p>You may consult this list to find the Privacy Policy for each of the advertising partners of android app.</p>
<p>Third-party ad servers or ad networks uses technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons that are used in their respective advertisements and links that appear on android app, which are sent directly to users' browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.</p>
<p>Note that android app has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.</p>
<h2>Third-Party Privacy Policies</h2>
<p>android app's Privacy Policy does not apply to other advertisers or websites. Thus, we are advising you to consult the respective Privacy Policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information. It may include their practices and instructions about how to opt-out of certain options.</p>
<p>You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To know more detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers, it can be found at the browsers' respective websites.</p>
<h2>CCPA Privacy Rights (Do Not Sell My Personal Information)</h2>
<p>Under the CCPA, among other rights, California consumers have the right to:</p>
<p>Request that a business that collects a consumer's personal data disclose the categories and specific pieces of personal data that a business has collected about consumers.</p>
<p>Request that a business delete any personal data about the consumer that a business has collected.</p>
<p>Request that a business that sells a consumer's personal data, not sell the consumer's personal data.</p>
<p>If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.</p>
<h2>GDPR Data Protection Rights</h2>
<p>We would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:</p>
<p>The right to access – You have the right to request copies of your personal data. We may charge you a small fee for this service.</p>
<p>The right to rectification – You have the right to request that we correct any information you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request that we complete the information you believe is incomplete.</p>
<p>The right to erasure – You have the right to request that we erase your personal data, under certain conditions.</p>
<p>The right to restrict processing – You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.</p>
<p>The right to object to processing – You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.</p>
<p>The right to data portability – You have the right to request that we transfer the data that we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.</p>
<p>If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.</p>
<h2>Children's Information</h2>
<p>Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.</p>
<p>android app and codeavenge does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Best Online C Compiler: A Comprehensive Review</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/the-best-online-c-compiler-a-comprehensive-review/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/the-best-online-c-compiler-a-comprehensive-review/</id>
        <media:content url="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/14/The-Best-Online-C-Compiler-2.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-08-13T18:05:15+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/14/The-Best-Online-C-Compiler-2.jpeg" alt="Featured image of online c compiler" />
                    Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/14/The-Best-Online-C-Compiler-2.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Featured image of online c compiler" /></p>
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-44-42-GDB-online-Debugger-Compiler---Code-Compile-Run-Debug-online-C-C-2.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:1080,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;OnlineGDB home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-15-codepad.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Codepad IDE&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-55-Online-editor-and-compiler.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Paiza online IDE home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-46-13-Online-C-Compiler.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Programiz online IDE&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.onlinegdb.com/&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;http://codepad.org/&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://paiza.io/en&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.programiz.com/c-programming/online-compiler/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. In this article, we will be reviewing the top 5 best online C compilers.&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;OnlineGDB&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: OnlineGDB is a free online C compiler that provides a simple interface for writing and testing C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in debugger that allows you to step through your code and catch errors. Additionally, it offers a collaborative platform where you can share your code with others and work on projects together.&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;2. &quot;],[0,[1],1,&quot;Codepad&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Codepad is a popular online C compiler that provides a simple and clean interface. It offers the ability to write and run code in a variety of programming languages, including C. It">
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-55-Online-editor-and-compiler.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Paiza online IDE home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-46-13-Online-C-Compiler.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Programiz online IDE&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://paiza.io/en&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.programiz.com/c-programming/online-compiler/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;3. &quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;Paiza.IO&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Paiza.IO is a free online C compiler that provides a clean and intuitive interface for writing and running C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in code editor and debugger. Additionally, it allows you to save and share your code with others.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;4. Comeau C/C++: Comeau C/C++ is a website that offers a free online C compiler. It is a great resource for C programmers who need to test their code quickly without having to install software on their local machines. The website provides a simple interface for writing and testing your code.&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;5. &quot;],[0,[1],1,&quot;Programiz&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Programiz is a website that offers a comprehensive set of tutorials and tools for learning and practicing C programming. It provides an online code editor that allows you to write and test your C code directly from your browser. Additionally, it offers a variety of useful features, such as a code editor, compiler, and debugger.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;In conclusion, there are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. The compilers listed above are the top 5 best online C compilers that provide a simple and intuitive interface for writing and testing C code. So, choose the one that suits your needs and start programming!&quot;]]]]}">
<div>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-44-42-GDB-online-Debugger-Compiler---Code-Compile-Run-Debug-online-C-C-2.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:1080,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;OnlineGDB home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-15-codepad.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Codepad IDE&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.onlinegdb.com/&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;http://codepad.org/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. In this article, we will be reviewing the top 5 best online C compilers.&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;OnlineGDB&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: OnlineGDB is a free online C compiler that provides a simple interface for writing and testing C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in debugger that allows you to step through your code and catch errors. Additionally, it offers a collaborative platform where you can share your code with others and work on projects together.&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;2. &quot;],[0,[1],1,&quot;Codepad&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Codepad is a popular online C compiler that provides a simple and clean interface. It offers the ability to write and run code in a variety of programming languages, including C. It">
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-44-42-GDB-online-Debugger-Compiler---Code-Compile-Run-Debug-online-C-C-2.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:1080,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;OnlineGDB home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-15-codepad.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Codepad IDE&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.onlinegdb.com/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. In this article, we will be reviewing the top 5 best online C compilers.&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;OnlineGDB&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: OnlineGDB is a free online C compiler that provides a simple interface for writing and testing C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in debugger that allows you to step through your code and catch errors. Additionally, it offers a collaborative platform where you can share your code with others and work on projects together.&quot;]]],[10,1]]}">
<div>
<p>Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. In this article, we will be reviewing the top 5 best online C compilers.</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-44-42-GDB-online-Debugger-Compiler---Code-Compile-Run-Debug-online-C-C-2.jpeg" data-is-external-image="true">
<p>1.<a href="https://www.onlinegdb.com/">OnlineGDB</a>: OnlineGDB is a free online C compiler that provides a simple interface for writing and testing C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in debugger that allows you to step through your code and catch errors. Additionally, it offers a collaborative platform where you can share your code with others and work on projects together.</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-15-codepad.jpeg" data-is-external-image="true"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-44-42-GDB-online-Debugger-Compiler---Code-Compile-Run-Debug-online-C-C-2.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:1080,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;OnlineGDB home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-15-codepad.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Codepad IDE&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.onlinegdb.com/&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;http://codepad.org/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. In this article, we will be reviewing the top 5 best online C compilers.&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;OnlineGDB&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: OnlineGDB is a free online C compiler that provides a simple interface for writing and testing C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in debugger that allows you to step through your code and catch errors. Additionally, it offers a collaborative platform where you can share your code with others and work on projects together.&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;2. &quot;],[0,[1],1,&quot;Codepad&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Codepad is a popular online C compiler that provides a simple and clean interface. It offers the ability to write and run code in a variety of programming languages, including C. It">Codepad: Codepad is a popular online C compiler that provides a simple and clean interface. It offers the ability to write and run code in a variety of programming languages, including C. It's a great resource for testing code snippets or sharing code with others for debugging purposes.</div>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-44-42-GDB-online-Debugger-Compiler---Code-Compile-Run-Debug-online-C-C-2.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:1080,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;OnlineGDB home page&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-15-codepad.jpeg&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:1920,&quot;height&quot;:994,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Codepad IDE&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.onlinegdb.com/&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;http://codepad.org/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Are you a programmer looking for an online C compiler? With the advancements in technology, you no longer need to install software on your computer to compile and run C code. There are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. In this article, we will be reviewing the top 5 best online C compilers.&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;OnlineGDB&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: OnlineGDB is a free online C compiler that provides a simple interface for writing and testing C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in debugger that allows you to step through your code and catch errors. Additionally, it offers a collaborative platform where you can share your code with others and work on projects together.&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;2. &quot;],[0,[1],1,&quot;Codepad&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Codepad is a popular online C compiler that provides a simple and clean interface. It offers the ability to write and run code in a variety of programming languages, including C. It"> </div>
</div>
<div><img loading="lazy" src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-45-55-Online-editor-and-compiler.jpeg" data-is-external-image="true">
<p>3. <a href="https://paiza.io/en">Paiza.IO</a>: Paiza.IO is a free online C compiler that provides a clean and intuitive interface for writing and running C code. It supports multiple programming languages and has a built-in code editor and debugger. Additionally, it allows you to save and share your code with others.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>4. Comeau C/C++: Comeau C/C++ is a website that offers a free online C compiler. It is a great resource for C programmers who need to test their code quickly without having to install software on their local machines. The website provides a simple interface for writing and testing your code.</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-12-at-05-46-13-Online-C-Compiler.jpeg" data-is-external-image="true">
<p>5. <a href="https://www.programiz.com/c-programming/online-compiler/">Programiz</a>: Programiz is a website that offers a comprehensive set of tutorials and tools for learning and practicing C programming. It provides an online code editor that allows you to write and test your C code directly from your browser. Additionally, it offers a variety of useful features, such as a code editor, compiler, and debugger.</p>
<p>In conclusion, there are many online C compilers available that can be accessed through your web browser. The compilers listed above are the top 5 best online C compilers that provide a simple and intuitive interface for writing and testing C code. So, choose the one that suits your needs and start programming!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Streamline Your React Development with Prettier: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/streamline-your-react-development-with-prettier-a-step-by-step-guide/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/streamline-your-react-development-with-prettier-a-step-by-step-guide/</id>

        <updated>2023-08-13T18:06:41+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Prettier is a popular code formatter that helps keep your code clean and consistent. In this article, we'll go over how to set up and use Prettier in a React JS project. There are several reasons why you should consider using Prettier in your React&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;npm install --save-dev prettier&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;bash&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;yarn add prettier -D&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;csharp&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;{\n  \&quot;arrowParens\&quot;: true,\n  \&quot;bracketSpacing\&quot;: true,\n  \&quot;jsxBracketSameLine\&quot;: false,\n  \&quot;printWidth\&quot;: 80,\n  \&quot;semi\&quot;: true,\n  \&quot;singleQuote\&quot;: true,\n  \&quot;trailingComma\&quot;: \&quot;es5\&quot;,\n  \&quot;vueIndentScriptAndStyle\&quot;: false\n}&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;json&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;npx prettier --write src&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;bash&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;npx prettier --interactive&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;bash&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;npx prettier --check src&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;bash&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;\&quot;scripts\&quot;: {\n  \&quot;format\&quot;: \&quot;prettier --write src\&quot;\n},&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;json&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;npm run format&quot;,&quot;language&quot;:&quot;bash&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;code&quot;]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Prettier is a popular code formatter that helps keep your code clean and consistent. In this article, we">
<div>
<p>Prettier is a popular code formatter that helps keep your code clean and consistent. In this article, we'll go over how to set up and use Prettier in a React JS project.</p>
<h2>Why Use Prettier?</h2>
<p>There are several reasons why you should consider using Prettier in your React project:</p>
<h3>Consistency</h3>
<p>One of the biggest advantages of using Prettier is that it helps ensure consistency across your codebase. By default, Prettier uses a set of rules to format your code, which means that all team members will be following the same formatting conventions. This makes it easier for developers to work together on the same codebase and reduces the risk of conflicts during code reviews.</p>
<h3>Efficiency</h3>
<p>Another advantage of using Prettier is that it saves time and effort. Instead of manually formatting your code, Prettier does it for you, which means you can focus on writing code rather than worrying about formatting.</p>
<h3>Improved Code Quality</h3>
<p>Prettier not only formats your code but also helps improve its quality. For example, it can detect and fix issues such as missing semicolons, mismatched brackets, and unnecessary whitespace.</p>
<h2>Setting Up Prettier in a React Project</h2>
<p>To set up Prettier in a React project, follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Install Prettier</li>
</ol>
<p>First, install Prettier using npm or yarn:</p>
<p>or</p>
<ol>
<li>Create a <code>.prettierrc</code> File</li>
</ol>
<p>Next, create a <code>.prettierrc</code> file in the root of your project. This file contains the configuration settings for Prettier.</p>
<p>Here's an example <code>.prettierrc</code> file:</p>
<p>The above configuration sets up Prettier to use arrow functions with parentheses, enable bracket spacing, disable JSX bracket same line, set the print width to 80 characters, use semi-colons, single quotes, and trailing commas for ES5 syntax. You can adjust these settings according to your preferences.</p>
<ol>
<li>Add Prettier to Your IDE</li>
</ol>
<p>If you're using an Integrated Development Environment (IDE), you may need to configure it to use Prettier. For example, if you're using Visual Studio Code, you can install the Prettier extension and configure it to format your code on save.</p>
<h2>Using Prettier in Your React Project</h2>
<p>Now that Prettier is set up, let's see how to use it in your React project.</p>
<ol>
<li>Format Your Code</li>
</ol>
<p>To format your code using Prettier, simply run the following command in your terminal:</p>
<p>This command formats all the files in the <code>src</code> folder and writes the changes back to the original files.</p>
<p>Alternatively, you can also format your code interactively using the Prettier CLI. To do this, run the following command:</p>
<p>This opens an interactive interface where you can select the files you want to format and choose the formatting options.</p>
<ol>
<li>Check Code Style</li>
</ol>
<p>To check your code style without modifying anything, you can run the following command:</p>
<p>This command checks your code style against the Prettier rules and reports any violations.</p>
<ol>
<li>Auto format On Save</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, you can configure Prettier to auto format your code on save. To do this, add the following script to your <code>package.json</code> file:</p>
<p>Then, run the following command to link the script to your IDE:</p>
<p>Now, whenever you save a file, Prettier will automatically format it according to your configured settings.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Use Vite for React App Generation</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/how-to-use-vite-for-react-app-generation/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/how-to-use-vite-for-react-app-generation/</id>

        <updated>2023-08-13T18:05:51+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Wait for the generation process to complete. Depending on your machine's speed, this may take a few seconds or minutes. Once the generation process is finished, navigate into your new app directory by running cd my-app. You should now see a basic React app structure,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;code&quot;]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;React is a powerful JavaScript library for building user interfaces, and Vite is a modern front-end build tool that simplifies the development process. In this article, we will explore how to use Vite to generate React apps, and how it can improve your development workflow.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Getting Started with Vite:&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Before we dive into generating React apps with Vite, let">
<ul>
<li>Wait for the generation process to complete. Depending on your machine's speed, this may take a few seconds or minutes.</li>
<li>Once the generation process is finished, navigate into your new app directory by running <code>cd my-app</code>.</li>
<li>You should now see a basic React app structure, including a <code>src</code> folder containing components, pages, and utilities.</li>
</ul>
<p>Customizing Your React App:</p>
<p>One of the benefits of using Vite is its flexibility and customization options. Let's explore how to modify your newly generated React app to suit your needs.</p>
<ol>
<li>Change the app name and description by modifying the <code>package.json</code> file. Update the <code>name</code> and <code>description</code> fields to reflect your app's new identity.</li>
<li>Update the app's dependencies by running <code>vite dep check</code> and installing any required packages.</li>
<li>Modify the app's layout and styling by editing the <code>index.html</code> file in the <code>public</code> directory. You can add your own HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code to create a unique look and feel.</li>
<li>Add new components, pages, and utilities by creating new files within the <code>src</code> directory. Use the <code>vite create</code> command to generate new files and directories.</li>
<li>Optimize your app's performance by configuring Webpack, Babel, and other tools through Vite's configuration files.</li>
</ol>
<p>Building and Deploying Your React App:</p>
<p>Once you've customized your React app, you're ready to build and deploy it. Vite makes this process easy with its built-in build and deployment tools.</p>
<ol>
<li>Run <code>vite build</code> to compile your app's code and create a production-ready bundle.</li>
<li>Run <code>vite serve</code> to start a local development server and test your app in real-time.</li>
<li>When you're ready to deploy, run <code>vite deploy</code> to export your app's code to a static website or upload it to a hosting platform.</li>
</ol>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Improve Your Coding Skills: A Simple Guide</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/how-to-improve-your-coding-skills-a-simple-guide/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/how-to-improve-your-coding-skills-a-simple-guide/</id>
        <media:content url="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/13/How-to-Improve-Your-Coding-Skills-A-Simple-Guide.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-08-13T18:03:14+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/13/How-to-Improve-Your-Coding-Skills-A-Simple-Guide.jpeg" alt="Coding in a desk" />
                    Coding is an essential skill for anyone looking to work in the tech industry. Whether you are a beginner or a seasoned programmer, there is always room for improvement. In this article, we will discuss some tips to help you improve your coding skills. In&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/13/How-to-Improve-Your-Coding-Skills-A-Simple-Guide.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Coding in a desk" /></p>
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Coding is an essential skill for anyone looking to work in the tech industry. Whether you are a beginner or a seasoned programmer, there is always room for improvement. In this article, we will discuss some tips to help you improve your coding skills.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ol&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Practice, practice, practice: The more you code, the better you get. Set aside time each day to practice coding. This can be as simple as solving programming challenges or working on your own projects. Don">
<div>
<p>Coding is an essential skill for anyone looking to work in the tech industry. Whether you are a beginner or a seasoned programmer, there is always room for improvement. In this article, we will discuss some tips to help you improve your coding skills.</p>
<ol>
<li>Practice, practice, practice: The more you code, the better you get. Set aside time each day to practice coding. This can be as simple as solving programming challenges or working on your own projects. Don't be afraid to experiment and try new things.</li>
<li>Learn a new programming language: Learning a new programming language can expand your horizons and improve your overall coding skills. It can also make you more marketable in the job market. Start with a language that is popular or relevant to your field.</li>
<li>Read and write code: Read code written by other developers to learn new techniques and best practices. Write code yourself to apply what you have learned. You can also contribute to open-source projects to gain experience and build your portfolio.</li>
<li>Join a coding community: Joining a coding community can help you learn from others and get feedback on your work. Look for online communities or attend local meetups to connect with other developers. You can also participate in coding challenges or hackathons to test your skills.</li>
<li>Take online courses: Online courses are a great way to learn new skills and stay up-to-date with the latest programming languages and technologies. Many online platforms offer free or low-cost courses, such as Coursera, Udacity, and Codecademy.</li>
<li>Use coding tools: Coding tools can help you streamline your workflow and improve your coding skills. For example, text editors like Sublime Text and Visual Studio Code can improve your coding speed and efficiency. Version control systems like Git can help you manage your code and collaborate with others.</li>
<li>Get feedback: Feedback is essential for improving your coding skills. Ask other developers to review your code and provide feedback. This can help you identify areas for improvement and learn new techniques. You can also use online platforms like GitHub to get feedback on your code.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, improving your coding skills takes time and effort. By practicing regularly, learning new languages, reading and writing code, joining a coding community, taking online courses, using coding tools, and getting feedback, you can become a better programmer. Remember to stay curious and always be willing to learn.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A review of the top libraries and tools for Android development</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/a-review-of-the-top-libraries-and-tools-for-android-development/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/a-review-of-the-top-libraries-and-tools-for-android-development/</id>

        <updated>2023-08-13T17:58:27+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Here is a brief overview of some of the top libraries and tools that are commonly used in Android development: These are just a few examples of the many libraries and tools that are available for Android development. There are many others to choose from,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Here is a brief overview of some of the top libraries and tools that are commonly used in Android development:&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ol&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Android Studio: Android Studio is the official Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for Android development. It is based on the IntelliJ IDEA platform and provides a powerful set of features for building, testing, and debugging Android apps.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Retrofit: Retrofit is a type-safe HTTP client for Android and Java. It makes it easy to send and receive data from a server, and it supports a wide range of data formats, including JSON, XML, and HTML.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;RxJava: RxJava is a reactive programming library for Android and Java. It allows developers to write asynchronous, event-based code, which is often easier to read and maintain than traditional, callback-based code.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Dagger: Dagger is a dependency injection framework for Android and Java. It simplifies the process of injecting dependencies into your app, making it easier to test and maintain.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Butter Knife: Butter Knife is a view binding library for Android. It lets you bind your Android views to your data sources using simple annotations, reducing the amount of boilerplate code you need to write.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Realm: Realm is a mobile database that is optimized for Android and iOS. It offers a simple, yet powerful API for storing and querying data on the device, and it is much faster and more efficient than SQLite.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Glide: Glide is an image loading library for Android that is focused on smooth scrolling. It allows you to load and display images from a variety of sources, and it has a number of features that make it easier to display images in your app, such as caching and transformations.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;LeakCanary: LeakCanary is a memory leak detection library for Android. It automatically detects and helps you fix memory leaks in your app, so you can avoid common memory management issues that can cause your app to crash or drain the battery.&quot;]]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;These are just a few examples of the many libraries and tools that are available for Android development. There are many others to choose from, and the right ones for you will depend on your specific needs and preferences.&quot;]]]]}">
<div>
<p>Here is a brief overview of some of the top libraries and tools that are commonly used in Android development:</p>
<ol>
<li>Android Studio: Android Studio is the official Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for Android development. It is based on the IntelliJ IDEA platform and provides a powerful set of features for building, testing, and debugging Android apps.</li>
<li>Retrofit: Retrofit is a type-safe HTTP client for Android and Java. It makes it easy to send and receive data from a server, and it supports a wide range of data formats, including JSON, XML, and HTML.</li>
<li>RxJava: RxJava is a reactive programming library for Android and Java. It allows developers to write asynchronous, event-based code, which is often easier to read and maintain than traditional, callback-based code.</li>
<li>Dagger: Dagger is a dependency injection framework for Android and Java. It simplifies the process of injecting dependencies into your app, making it easier to test and maintain.</li>
<li>Butter Knife: Butter Knife is a view binding library for Android. It lets you bind your Android views to your data sources using simple annotations, reducing the amount of boilerplate code you need to write.</li>
<li>Realm: Realm is a mobile database that is optimized for Android and iOS. It offers a simple, yet powerful API for storing and querying data on the device, and it is much faster and more efficient than SQLite.</li>
<li>Glide: Glide is an image loading library for Android that is focused on smooth scrolling. It allows you to load and display images from a variety of sources, and it has a number of features that make it easier to display images in your app, such as caching and transformations.</li>
<li>LeakCanary: LeakCanary is a memory leak detection library for Android. It automatically detects and helps you fix memory leaks in your app, so you can avoid common memory management issues that can cause your app to crash or drain the battery.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are just a few examples of the many libraries and tools that are available for Android development. There are many others to choose from, and the right ones for you will depend on your specific needs and preferences.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Some tips to convert Java to Kotlin language</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/some-tips-to-convert-java-to-kotlin-language/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/some-tips-to-convert-java-to-kotlin-language/</id>

        <updated>2023-08-13T18:00:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Java and Kotlin are both popular programming languages for developing Android apps. While Java is the most widely used language for Android development, Kotlin is a newer language that offers a number of benefits over Java, including improved readability and conciseness, better support for functional&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="" data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Java and Kotlin are both popular programming languages for developing Android apps. While Java is the most widely used language for Android development, Kotlin is a newer language that offers a number of benefits over Java, including improved readability and conciseness, better support for functional programming, and full interoperability with Java.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;If you are a Java developer looking to learn Kotlin, here are some tips to help you with the transition:&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ol&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Start small: Don">
<div>
<p>Java and Kotlin are both popular programming languages for developing Android apps. While Java is the most widely used language for Android development, Kotlin is a newer language that offers a number of benefits over Java, including improved readability and conciseness, better support for functional programming, and full interoperability with Java.</p>
<p>If you are a Java developer looking to learn Kotlin, here are some tips to help you with the transition:</p>
<ol>
<li>Start small: Don't try to convert your entire Java codebase to Kotlin all at once. Instead, start with a small, self-contained project or a single class, and gradually convert more and more code as you become more familiar with Kotlin.</li>
<li>Use the Kotlin conversion tool: The Kotlin plugin for Android Studio includes a built-in tool for converting Java code to Kotlin. While this tool is not perfect, it can save you a lot of time and effort by automatically generating a lot of the boilerplate code for you.</li>
<li>Understand the differences between Java and Kotlin: Kotlin and Java have some significant differences in their syntax and semantics, so it's important to learn these differences and how they affect your code. For example, Kotlin does not have the same concept of checked exceptions as Java, and it has different rules for nullability and immutability.</li>
<li>Take advantage of Kotlin's type inference: Kotlin has a powerful type inference system that allows you to write code that is more concise and easier to read. In many cases, you can omit type declarations entirely, and the compiler will infer the correct types based on the context.</li>
<li>Use Kotlin's features to improve your code: Kotlin has a number of features that are not present in Java, such as extension functions, data classes, and inline functions. These features can help you write cleaner, more readable code that is easier to maintain.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, the transition from Java to Kotlin can be challenging, but it is well worth the effort. Kotlin is a modern, powerful language that offers many benefits over Java, and it is becoming the language of choice for many Android developers. With the right approach and the right tools, you can learn Kotlin and start using it to write better, more efficient code for your Android apps.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Install Postgres using docker</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/install-postgres-using-docker/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/install-postgres-using-docker/</id>
        <media:content url="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/8/install-postgres-on-linux.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-08-13T17:57:42+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/8/install-postgres-on-linux.png" alt="Install postgresql using docker" />
                    PostgreSQL is a powerful, open source object-relational database system with over 35 years of active development that has earned it a strong reputation for reliability, feature robustness, and performance.There is a wealth of information to be found describing how to install and use PostgreSQL through&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/8/install-postgres-on-linux.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Install postgresql using docker" /></p>
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;docker pull postgres:latest\n&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;docker run --name postgres -e POSTGRES_USER=name -e POSTGRES_PASSWORD=mypass -p 5432:5432 -d postgres:latest\n&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;docker ps\n&quot;}],[&quot;code&quot;,{&quot;code&quot;:&quot;docker exec -it postgres psql -U name\n&quot;}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;PostgreSQL is a powerful, open source object-relational database system with over 35 years of active development that has earned it a strong reputation for reliability, feature robustness, and performance.&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;There is a wealth of information to be found describing how to install and use PostgreSQL through the official documentation. The open source community community provides many helpful places to become familiar with PostgreSQL, discover how it works, and find career opportunities. Learm more on how to engage with the community.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;h3&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Pre requirements&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;To install PostgreSQL you need to have docker installed on you device. See official documentation how to install docker on your Linux device &quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot; .&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.Install latest version PostgreSQL using docker by running this command&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;2.Run this single command to set password, user name, container name&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;3.Check if your PostgreSQL container is up and running&quot;]]],[10,2],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;If your want to connect to PostgreSQL in Docker container execute this command&quot;]]],[10,3]]}">
<div>
<p>PostgreSQL is a powerful, open source object-relational database system with over 35 years of active development that has earned it a strong reputation for reliability, feature robustness, and performance.There is a wealth of information to be found describing how to install and use PostgreSQL through the official documentation. The open source community community provides many helpful places to become familiar with PostgreSQL, discover how it works, and find career opportunities. Learm more on how to engage with the community.</p>
<h3>Pre requirements</h3>
<p>To install PostgreSQL you need to have docker installed on you device. See official documentation how to install docker on your Linux device <a href="https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/">https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/</a> .</p>
<p>1.Install latest version PostgreSQL using docker by running this command</p>
<blockquote>
<p>docker pull postgres:latest</p>
</blockquote>
<p>2.Run this single command to set password, user name, container name</p>
<blockquote>
<p>docker run --name postgres -e POSTGRES_USER=name -e POSTGRES_PASSWORD=mypass -p 5432:5432 -d postgres:latest</p>
</blockquote>
<p>3.Check if your PostgreSQL container is up and running</p>
<blockquote>
<p>docker ps</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If your want to connect to PostgreSQL in Docker container execute this command</p>
<blockquote>
<p>docker exec -it postgres psql -U name</p>
</blockquote>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Some Popular Heroku alternatives</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/some-popular-heroku-alternatives/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/some-popular-heroku-alternatives/</id>
        <media:content url="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/7/website-thumbnail-1.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="opensource"/>
            <category term="heroku"/>
            <category term="blog"/>
            <category term="alternative"/>

        <updated>2023-08-13T17:55:52+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/7/website-thumbnail-1.png" alt="" />
                    Render: Render is the easiest cloud for developers and teams to deploy any app or website. You can deploy anything on Render, from simple static sites and cron jobs to databases and Dockerized private services. Render deploys your services directly from GitHub or GitLab. All&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://codeavenge.com/media/posts/7/website-thumbnail-1.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://render.com/register&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Heroku no longer offer free tier. So here is some Heroku alternative that can help you to develop your mini project&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;1.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;Render&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Render is the easiest cloud for developers and teams to deploy any app or website.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;You can deploy anything on Render, from simple static sites and cron jobs to databases and Dockerized private services.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Render deploys your services directly from GitHub or GitLab. All that">Render: Render is the easiest cloud for developers and teams to deploy any app or website.
<ul>
<li>You can deploy anything on Render, from simple static sites and cron jobs to databases and Dockerized private services.</li>
<li>Render deploys your services directly from GitHub or GitLab. All that's needed is to push your code like you normally do — Render automatically updates your services and keeps them up and running at all times.Screenshots:</li>
</ul>
<figure class="center db"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2022/11/Screenshot-from-2022-11-23-13-34-59.resized.png" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://fly.io/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;2.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;Fly.io&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Fly provide free tier with free PostgreSQL.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Building Social Music App With Phoenix LiveView&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Deploy your Pheonix application&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Turbocharge Your Heroku Apps With New Turboku&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Run a Remix App&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;Screenshots:&quot;]]]]]}">
<div>
<p>2.<a href="https://fly.io/">Fly.io</a>: Fly provide free tier with free PostgreSQL.</p>
<ul>
<li>Building Social Music App With Phoenix LiveView</li>
<li>Deploy your Pheonix application</li>
<li>Turbocharge Your Heroku Apps With New Turboku</li>
<li>Run a Remix AppScreenshots:</li>
</ul>
<figure class="center db"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2022/11/Screenshot-from-2022-11-27-15-59-09.resized.png" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://m.do.co/c/f5b3ec26dde2&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;3.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;DigitalOCean&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: If you are a student, by using GitHub education pack you can get one 100$ for one year free credit. And my refereing others you can also get more credit to use.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Deploy react application&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Make new virtual machine&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Host own server, static, dynamic website&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Host databases like mongodb, PostgreSQL, MySQL&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Add your own domain&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;Screenshots:&quot;]]]]]}">
<div>
<p>3.<a href="https://m.do.co/c/f5b3ec26dde2">DigitalOCean</a>: If you are a student, by using GitHub education pack you can get one 100$ for one year free credit. And my refereing others you can also get more credit to use.</p>
<ul>
<li>Deploy react application</li>
<li>Make new virtual machine</li>
<li>Host own server, static, dynamic website</li>
<li>Host databases like mongodb, PostgreSQL, MySQL</li>
<li>Add your own domainScreenshots:</li>
</ul>
<figure class="center db"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2022/11/Screenshot-from-2022-11-23-13-33-50.resized.png" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;4.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;Netlify&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: The fastest way to combine your favorite tools and APIs to build the fastest sites, stores, and apps for the web. It is fee for personal use.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Managing environment variables from your terminal with Netlify CLI&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;New Command Palette to help you work faster in the Netlify UI&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Quirrel Joins Netlify and Scheduled Functions Launches in Beta&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Supercharge your local development with Netlify Dev&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Handling multiple accounts with Netlify CLI&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;Screenshots:&quot;]]]]]}">
<div>
<p>4.<a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify</a>: The fastest way to combine your favorite tools and APIs to build the fastest sites, stores, and apps for the web. It is fee for personal use.</p>
<ul>
<li>Managing environment variables from your terminal with Netlify CLI</li>
<li>New Command Palette to help you work faster in the Netlify UI</li>
<li>Quirrel Joins Netlify and Scheduled Functions Launches in Beta</li>
<li>Supercharge your local development with Netlify Dev</li>
<li>Handling multiple accounts with Netlify CLIScreenshots:</li>
</ul>
<figure class="center db"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2022/11/Screenshot-from-2022-11-23-13-33-39.resized.png" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://railway.app?referralCode=RLF3yD&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;5.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;Railway.app&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Railway is an infrastructure platform where you can provision infrastructure, develop with that infrastructure locally, and then deploy to the cloud.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Start from scratch or pick a template to deploy instantly, from bots to blogs&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Keep Environment Variables and Secrets for your team, securely, in one place&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Add a cron job, a database, or another (micro)service! Railway grows with your application&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Connect to your infrastructure + secrets, from any terminal in the world&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Evolve your application over time, with fork joinable environments.&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;Screenshots:&quot;]]]]]}">
<div>
<p>5.<a href="https://railway.app?referralCode=RLF3yD">Railway.app</a>: Railway is an infrastructure platform where you can provision infrastructure, develop with that infrastructure locally, and then deploy to the cloud.</p>
<ul>
<li>Start from scratch or pick a template to deploy instantly, from bots to blogs</li>
<li>Keep Environment Variables and Secrets for your team, securely, in one place</li>
<li>Add a cron job, a database, or another (micro)service! Railway grows with your application</li>
<li>Connect to your infrastructure + secrets, from any terminal in the world</li>
<li>Evolve your application over time, with fork joinable environments.Screenshots:</li>
</ul>
<figure class="center db"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2022/11/Screenshot-from-2022-11-27-15-59-25.resized.png" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/cloud-computing/openshift&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;6.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;OpenShift&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Red Hat® OpenShift® is an enterprise-ready Kubernetes container platform built for an open hybrid cloud strategy. It provides a consistent application platform to manage hybrid cloud, multicloud, and edge deployments.&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ul&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Deploy applications closer to your users and data&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Gain end-to-end visibility and control for your Kubernetes clusters&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Red Hat OpenShift includes hundreds of fixes to defects, security, and performance issues for upstream Kubernetes in every release&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;It includes software-defined networking and validates additional common networking solutions&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;Screenshots:&quot;]]]]]}">
<div>
<p>6.<a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/cloud-computing/openshift">OpenShift</a>: Red Hat® OpenShift® is an enterprise-ready Kubernetes container platform built for an open hybrid cloud strategy. It provides a consistent application platform to manage hybrid cloud, multicloud, and edge deployments.</p>
<ul>
<li>Deploy applications closer to your users and data</li>
<li>Gain end-to-end visibility and control for your Kubernetes clusters</li>
<li>Red Hat OpenShift includes hundreds of fixes to defects, security, and performance issues for upstream Kubernetes in every release</li>
<li>It includes software-defined networking and validates additional common networking solutionsScreenshots:</li>
</ul>
<figure class="center db"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://codeavenge.com/content/images/2022/11/Screenshot-from-2022-11-23-13-34-07.resized.png" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}],[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;a&quot;],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://vercel.com/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;7.&quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;Firebase&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;: Firebase is described as ">
<div>
<p>7.<a>Firebase</a>: Firebase is described as 'gives you the tools and infrastructure to build better apps and grow successful businesses' and is a popular website in the development category.</p>
<ul>
<li>Easy to connect with other google services.</li>
<li>Freemium firebase database, works with android, ios, web</li>
<li>Accelerate and scale app development without managing infrastructure</li>
<li>Release with confidence and monitor performance and stability</li>
<li>Boost engagement with rich analytics, A/B testing, and messaging campaignsScreenshots:</li>
</ul>
<p>8.<a href="https://vercel.com/">Vercel</a>: Vercel is the platform for frontend developers, providing the speed and reliability innovators need to create at the moment of inspiration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Everything you need to build your site exactly how you imagine, from automatic API handling to built-in image and performance optimizations</li>
<li>Connect your pages to any data source, headless CMS, or API and make it work in everyone’s dev environment</li>
<li>From caching to Serverless Functions, all our cloud primitives work perfectly on localhost</li>
<li>Make frontend development a collaborative experience with automatic Preview Deployments for every code change, by seamlessly integrating with GitHub, GitLab, and Bitbucket</li>
<li>Automatic Previews for every branch Each new branch receives a live, production-like URL that everyone on your team can visit.Screenshots:</li>
</ul>
<p>There are also many more alternatives, just need to google it or need to ask your friend,teacher.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Install Telegram on Ubuntu, Pop-OS, Manjaro and other Linux distro</title>
        <author>
            <name>Anindra</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://codeavenge.com/install-telegram-on-ubuntu-pop-os-manjaro-and-other-linux-distro/"/>
        <id>https://codeavenge.com/install-telegram-on-ubuntu-pop-os-manjaro-and-other-linux-distro/</id>

        <updated>2023-08-13T17:44:28+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Telegram is one of the most popular messaging system that available in multiple platform, example: Linux, Windows, Mac, Android. This is a smiler messaging application like WhatsApp. According to Wikipedia they had 450+ million active users in Jan 2021 and that is a very large&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div data-mobiledoc="{&quot;version&quot;:&quot;0.3.2&quot;,&quot;atoms&quot;:[[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}],[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}],[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}],[&quot;soft-return&quot;,&quot;&quot;,{}]],&quot;cards&quot;:[[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/pasted-image-0.png&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:682,&quot;height&quot;:290,&quot;alt&quot;:&quot;Image source: Wikipedia&quot;}],[&quot;image&quot;,{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/JEJoTY9iB8kMrRkEWjBMmnSHWT8uvYmsMjLQojDIE9dDVv2GDE_wgSCu49GFWCbQvzPrJECUsWaPJCd3Jz6Q4I7cFDQgU2OYQmE8MCzqN0Gqiql3Au1klWOkchWJBIoslKCE5WR4=s0&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:702,&quot;height&quot;:234}]],&quot;markups&quot;:[[&quot;strong&quot;],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://snapcraft.io/telegram-desktop&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://desktop.telegram.org/&quot;]],[&quot;a&quot;,[&quot;href&quot;,&quot;https://flatpak.org/setup/&quot;]]],&quot;sections&quot;:[[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Telegram is one of the most popular messaging system that available in multiple platform, example: Linux, Windows, Mac, Android. This is a smiler messaging application like WhatsApp. According to Wikipedia they had 450+ million active users in Jan 2021 and that is a very large user base for a messaging application.&quot;]]],[10,0],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Unlike WhatsApp, Telegram have desktop client for multiple devices. Telegram desktop clients are open-source and free to use, available on GitHub.&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Features:&quot;]]],[3,&quot;ol&quot;,[[[0,[],0,&quot;Telegram available for 32bit and 64bit computer.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Available in Linux, Windows, macOS, iPadOS, iPhone, Android.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Telegram a combination of 256-bit symmetric AES encryption, 2048-bit RSA encryption, Diffie–Hellman secure key exchange. That make Telegram privacy focus application.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Can share large file in chat.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Telegram in free forever with no ads, no subscription charge.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;Telegram provide API that helps developer to make custom desktop.&quot;]],[[0,[],0,&quot;In their recent update users can change chat Themes, use many Interactive emojis, can read receipts in small groups also can record live streams and video chat.&quot;]]]],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Install for Ubuntu:&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Ubuntu 20.04, Ubuntu 18.04, Ubuntu 21.o4 comes with pre-installed package manager called &quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;snap&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot;, so it is easy to install Telegram in Ubuntu. To install Telegram, run this following commandsudo snap install telegram-dekstop&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;This command will install the latest and stable version snap Telegram. For more info, visit this link: &quot;],[0,[1],1,&quot;https://snapcraft.io/telegram-desktop&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Or can download telegram via apt package manager. This is the easy way to download Telegram in ubuntu, but it may or  may not install the latest release of telegram.sudo apt install telegram-dekstop&quot;]]],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Install for Pop OS, Linux mint, Ubuntu and other Ubuntu based distro:&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Go to official telegram website &quot;],[0,[2],1,&quot;https://desktop.telegram.org/&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot; and click on Get Telegram for Linux, this will download a &quot;],[0,[0],1,&quot;tar.xz&quot;],[0,[],0,&quot; . Now extract this tar filetar -xf tsetup-x64.3.1.1.exe&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Another waywget -O telegram.tar.xz https://updates.tdesktop.com/tlinux/tsetup.3.1.1.tar.xz&quot;],[1,[],0,0],[0,[],0,&quot;tar -xf telegram.tar.xz&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Then go to telegram folder and Telegram folder and give read, write and execute permission to Telegram applicationcd telegram/Telegram&quot;],[1,[],0,1],[0,[],0,&quot;chmod +x Telegam&quot;],[1,[],0,2],[0,[],0,&quot;sudo ./Telegram&quot;]]],[10,1],[1,&quot;h2&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Install Telegram in Manjaro (any Arch based distro) and any Linux distro:&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;Flat-hub package manager available in most of the popular Linux distro like Ubuntu, Manjaro, Linux Mint Manjaro etc. So it is easy to install telegram , not Only telegram also other application. If you think flathub is not available in your Linux desktop then follow this article to install &quot;],[0,[3],1,&quot;https://flatpak.org/setup/&quot;]]],[1,&quot;p&quot;,[[0,[],0,&quot;To install telegram run this following command to your terminalflatpak install flathub org.telegram.desktop&quot;],[1,[],0,3],[0,[],0,&quot;flatpak run org.telegram.desktop&quot;]]]]}">
<div>
<p>Telegram is one of the most popular messaging system that available in multiple platform, example: Linux, Windows, Mac, Android. This is a smiler messaging application like WhatsApp. According to Wikipedia they had 450+ million active users in Jan 2021 and that is a very large user base for a messaging application.</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/pasted-image-0.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/responsive/pasted-image-0-xs.png 300w ,file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/responsive/pasted-image-0-sm.png 480w ,file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/responsive/pasted-image-0-md.png 768w ,file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/responsive/pasted-image-0-lg.png 1024w ,file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/responsive/pasted-image-0-xl.png 1360w ,file:///home/anindra/Documents/Publii/sites/codeavenge/input/media/posts/5/responsive/pasted-image-0-2xl.png 1600w">
<p>Unlike WhatsApp, Telegram have desktop client for multiple devices. Telegram desktop clients are open-source and free to use, available on GitHub.</p>
<p>Features:</p>
<ol>
<li>Telegram available for 32bit and 64bit computer.</li>
<li>Available in Linux, Windows, macOS, iPadOS, iPhone, Android.</li>
<li>Telegram a combination of 256-bit symmetric AES encryption, 2048-bit RSA encryption, Diffie–Hellman secure key exchange. That make Telegram privacy focus application.</li>
<li>Can share large file in chat.</li>
<li>Telegram in free forever with no ads, no subscription charge.</li>
<li>Telegram provide API that helps developer to make custom desktop.</li>
<li>In their recent update users can change chat Themes, use many Interactive emojis, can read receipts in small groups also can record live streams and video chat.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Install for Ubuntu:</h2>
<p>Ubuntu 20.04, Ubuntu 18.04, Ubuntu 21.o4 comes with pre-installed package manager called <strong>snap</strong>, so it is easy to install Telegram in Ubuntu. To install Telegram, run this following commandsudo snap install telegram-dekstop</p>
<p>This command will install the latest and stable version snap Telegram. For more info, visit this link: <a href="https://snapcraft.io/telegram-desktop">https://snapcraft.io/telegram-desktop</a></p>
<p>Or can download telegram via apt package manager. This is the easy way to download Telegram in ubuntu, but it may or  may not install the latest release of telegram.sudo apt install telegram-dekstop</p>
<h2>Install for Pop OS, Linux mint, Ubuntu and other Ubuntu based distro:</h2>
<p>Go to official telegram website <a href="https://desktop.telegram.org/">https://desktop.telegram.org/</a> and click on Get Telegram for Linux, this will download a <strong>tar.xz</strong> . Now extract this tar filetar -xf tsetup-x64.3.1.1.exe</p>
<p>Another waywget -O telegram.tar.xz https://updates.tdesktop.com/tlinux/tsetup.3.1.1.tar.xztar -xf telegram.tar.xz</p>
<p>Then go to telegram folder and Telegram folder and give read, write and execute permission to Telegram applicationcd telegram/Telegramchmod +x Telegamsudo ./Telegram</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/JEJoTY9iB8kMrRkEWjBMmnSHWT8uvYmsMjLQojDIE9dDVv2GDE_wgSCu49GFWCbQvzPrJECUsWaPJCd3Jz6Q4I7cFDQgU2OYQmE8MCzqN0Gqiql3Au1klWOkchWJBIoslKCE5WR4=s0" data-is-external-image="true">
<h2>Install Telegram in Manjaro (any Arch based distro) and any Linux distro:</h2>
<p>Flat-hub package manager available in most of the popular Linux distro like Ubuntu, Manjaro, Linux Mint Manjaro etc. So it is easy to install telegram , not Only telegram also other application. If you think flathub is not available in your Linux desktop then follow this article to install <a href="https://flatpak.org/setup/">https://flatpak.org/setup/</a></p>
<p>To install telegram run this following command to your terminalflatpak install flathub org.telegram.desktopflatpak run org.telegram.desktop</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
